# DOMINIQUE MCPHAUL

dominiquemcphaul@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/dominique-mcphaul

portfolio website

Junior full stack developer with a passion for equitable and accessible technologies possessing 4+ years of experience working in Equity and Inclusion roles, three of which were served in a supervisory capacity. I love the potential that technology offers to create a more equitable world and want to contribute to a team that values the same tenet.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Mentor Me Collective** 

REMOTE

**User Experience Engineer, Equity Impact Advocate** 

**JUNE 2022 - PRESENT** 

- Executed quality assurance processes to ensure web design is aligned with organizational identity
- Researched and implemented new skills to improve usability and optimize productivity
- Worked collaboratively on an engineering team to speak through process improvement

#### THE BOLINGA BLACK CULTURAL RESOURCES CENTER

DAYTON, OH

**Program Coordinator** 

**JANUARY 2019 - JANUARY 2020** 

- Provided ongoing direction and leadership for program operations with two staff members, 12+ volunteers, and 42 program participants
- Managed web content updates and ongoing site maintenance to provide students with easy information access
- Designed program implementation and 3 year maintenance plan

# **Division of Student Affairs - Student Government Association**

DAYTON, OH

**Director of Diversity & Inclusion** 

**AUGUST 2017 - JUNE 2018** 

- Orchestrated efficient program development from conception through execution by collaborating cross-functionally across departments
- Implemented new campus wide projects, procedures, and programming strategies to resolve equity related concerns such as: expanding gender neutral restrooms, and equitable curriculum implementation
- Represented the student body serving as subject matter liaison for equitable campus practices and policies

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Foodie Friends**

- Social media application that connects users through their love of food
- Java based application with JavaScript front-end development and MySQL database management

#### The APEX Summit

- Web design project meant to be a single point of access for all conference information users might need
- Weebly was the primary, low code software used along with Google API embeds

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS & SOFTWARE TOOL**

Spring	υa	ιta	J٢	ľ
Spring		υd	Data	Data JF

- Python
- HTML/CSS

**Spring Boot** 

Java

- SQL
- Α
- Spring Security (JWT)
- Bootstrap
- REST API's

- **AWS Cloud**

Git

**SCRUM** 

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

**Generation USA** Wright State University Wright State University

Junior Full Stack Java Developer B.A. Biological Sciences (80 c.h. complete) B.S. Public Health (80 c.h. complete)

**APRIL 2022 - AUGUST 2022 AUGUST 2016 - JANUARY 2020 DECEMBER 2019 - JANUARY 2020** 

Unit Testing (JUnit, Mockito)

**SOLID OOP Principles** 

# **COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT & INTERESTS**

**University Presidents Ambassador NAACP** 

Ambassador Vice President, Political Action Chair DAYTON, OH DAYTON, OH